

Consultant seeking roles in Data Warehouse, Software Development, Database Management, Data Analysis, Data Extraction, Requirement Analysis, Performance Tuning, Unix Shell Scripting, Informatica, Oracle, SQL, PLSQL, Informatica Power Center, ETL Tool



Current Designation: Informatica and Oracle PLSQL Consultant Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: KPMG Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Mumbai Highest Degree: PG Diploma [Advance Computing]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore,Mumbai,Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Consultant, Software Development, Database Management, Data Analysis, Data Extraction, Requirement Analysis, Performance Tuning, Unix Shell Scripting, Informatica, Oracle, SQL, PLSQL, Informatica Power Center, ETL

Tool, Data Warehouse Developer, Data Warehousing

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

Over 7 Years programming experience as an Informatica Power Center 9.x and Oracle PL/SQL Developer involved in all phases of the SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle) from analysis, design, data transformation, data extraction, implementation and maintenance of Business Applications using ETL and Relational Database Management System (RDBMS) Extensively worked on data extraction, transformation and loading data from various sources like Oracle, SQL Server and Flat files.

Experience in design, develop, automate, and support of complex applications to extract, transform, and load data.

Extensively used Transformations like Filter, Aggregator, Joiner, Expression and Lookup, Update strategy and Sequence generator and Stored Procedure.

Work Experience

KPMG as Informatica and Oracle PLSQL Consultant Jul 2019 to Till Date

Extracted data from oracle database and spreadsheets and staged into a single place and applied business logic to load them in another database.

Tuned the performance of mappings by following Informatica best practices and applied several methods to get best performance by decreasing the run time of workflows.

Developed and maintained proper data extraction processes.

Created data mart for OFSAA application

Parameterized the mappings and increased the re-usability.

Assisted other ETL developers in solving complex scenarios and coordinated with source systems owners with day-to-day ETL progress monitoring.

Developed complex mappings in Informatica to load the data from various sources.

Created/Modified T2T Run for the PFT, FTP and ALM & LRM Module.

Designed and Developed Data Transformations in OFSAA.

Performed the performance and tuning at source, Target levels using Indexes, Hints and Partitioning in Oracle.

IBM India Pvt Ltd as Senior ETL and Database Developer.

Feb 2016 to Jun 2019

Prepared various mappings to load the data into different stages like Landing, Staging and Target tables.

Used various transformations like Source Qualifier, Expression, Aggregator, Joiner, Filter,

Lookup, and optimizing the Mapping.

Developed Workflows using task developer, worklet designer, and workflow designer in

Workflow manager and monitored the results using workflow monitor.

Investigated and implemented solutions for data quality issues.

Created PL/SQL scripts.

Developed and maintained proper data extraction processes.

Translated business into technical requirements.

Maintained Subversion code in accordance with company policy.

Writing technical documents using the functional specifications.

National Securities Depository Limited as PLSQL Developer

Jul 2015 to Feb 2016

Optimized the queries to improve the performance of the application. Involved in unit testing and bug fixing activity.

3i Infotech as Software Developer

Aug 2013 to Jul 2015

Developing packages, procedures, functions, and triggers for the application. Performing the tests on the newly coded procedures and documenting the same. Writing PL/SQL code using the technical and functional specifications. Creating Oracle objects like tables, types, packages, procedures and functions. Involved in bug fixing activity and unit testing.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical and Electronics) from K J Somaiya college of engineering, University of Mumbai in 2011

PG: PG Diploma (Advance Computing) from Centre for Development of Advanced Computing (CDAC) in 2013

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

1Z0-061 - Oracle Database 12c: SQL Fundamentals

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Unix Shell scripting,		2020	4 Year(s)
Oracle,plsql		2020	7 Year(s) 4 Month(s)
Informatica		2020	4 Year(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Marathi	Expert			
Gujarati	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time